Krystian Laskowski

Warsaw, Poland · krystianlaskowski1@gmail.com · 500622734 · https://klaskowski.github.io/

Вю

Krystian is a Full-stack Java Developer and a coding trainer. Tries to be "Multiplier", not just a maker. In his 7 years in the industry (and coding for 15 years in total), he took part in dozens of projects with millions of users for customers from US (both Silicon Valley and Wall Street Banking), Germany, Netherlands and his fatherland - Poland. What drives him is an infinite passion for solving people's problems with reasoning from first principles and software combined.

Technologies overlook

Main programming languages: Java, Typescript

Application types: Single page applications, Microservices

Databases: OracleDB, MySQL, MongoDB, Solr, ElasticSearch

Frameworks: Angular, React, Spring Boot, ExpressJS

EXPERIENCE

RedCompass

Warsaw / remote May 2020 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Taking part in development of D1R a highly configurable, production file test automation and analytics tool.
- Migrated from a Kibana dashboard to a full-fledged React application that visualises data and support testers in diagnosing payment processing issues.
- Technologies: Java 11, Groovy, Spring Boot, TypeScript, React, ElasticSearch, Docker, AWS.

Software Development Academy

Warsaw, Poland Dec 2018 - Present

Coding trainer

- SDA offers 6 months Java coding bootcamps in a 'from zero to Junior Java Developer' fashion.
- Trainers are responsible for reparing dedicated exercises and resources for students.
- Classes last 7 hours and occur on the weekend. They involve 80% practice 20% theory.
- Topics range from Java basics, Algorithms, through Unit testing, Design Patters, to Hibernate and Spring framework.

Pearson

Development Team Lead

San Jose, CA, US / remote Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Refined feature scope of Score Reports Project for Automated Language Test Engineering department.
- Broke up a Monolith, OracleDB sourced system into AWS-based microservices.
- Provided support for a team consisting of 3 people: Java Developer, QA Engineer and UX designer.
- Technologies: Java 8, Play! Framework, Angular, OracleDB, Docker AWS.

Ergo Digital IT

Warsaw, Poland

Full-stack developer

Aug 2018 - Jul 2019

- Migrated legacy systems into a cloud, microservice architecture.
- As a result, two registration and authentication systems (with distinct process) were merged under OpenIAM with Informatica warehouse as a data source.
- Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, Node.js, React, MongoDB, Openshift.

Citibank Europe PLC

Warsaw, Poland

Full-stack developer & Front-end Lead

Nov 2017 - Jul 2018

- Developed real-time risk analytics tools MAPS (Multi-asset portfolio system).
- Improved user experience and efficiency by introducing relevancy scoring to a multi-purpose search tool (using Solr as a storage and query engine).
- Improved automation and generating reports (generic, multi-dimensional charts, i.e. sankey chart, drilldown, bell curve / normal distribution).

• Technology stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Solr, Angular 6, HighCharts, KDB.

ING Bank (via Intive)

 $Frontend\ developer$

Wroclaw, Poland Dec 2015 - Oct 2017

- Developed single page application (also used via a web-view) for personal banking.
- Implemented Responsive UI's together with designers, maintaining custom components repository.
- Implemented WCAG standards into application (usability guidelines for people with disabilities).
- Technologies: Backbone.js, AngularJS, React, Angular, Polymer, Webpack, ExpressJS.

Firmao / Belcentrale (via Firmao)

- Full-stack developer
 - Developed Firmao CRM system features, e.g. integration with external SOAP/REST API (Google Calendar, Pingen).
 - Initiated a cooperation with Belcentrale, which ended up with creating a new distributed team and kick-off of a new social lending platform CapitalCircle.nl.
 - Technologies: Java 6, Scala, Play Framework, ExtJS.

EDUCATION

Wroclaw University of Technology MS Computer Science Wroclaw, Poland 2014 - 2016

Lodz University of Technology BS Computer Science - Game Design

Lodz, Poland 2009 - 2013

Interests

Stock trading, psychology